#### **VED PRAKASH**

Badheri, Samba, J&K, India vedvijayved@gmail.com Mob: 9906093931

#### **PERSONAL STATEMENT**

Qualified and experienced Materials Manager/Soldier, Over 16 years' service with ARMY ORDNANCE CORPS (logistic unit of Indian Army). Experience includes: I have a wealth of experience in clerical work, store management, coordinating manpower, resources, policy and expect high standards from both my peers and subordinates. I am a team player and carry out any tasks to the best of my ability and to a high standard. I also have gained experience of Training with National Scouts & Guides and awarded Certificate from Governor of Karnataka State. Field firing and battle inoculation every year and has been trained under simulated battle field conditions. Physical training in fire fighting and use of fire fighting appliances all through service. Having great knowledge in clerical and store management duties with diploma in Materials Management. Sufficient in exercising security measures to safeguard Government property from theft, sabotage and fire risk. Efficient in Maritime Security.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Ability to manage time and prioritize workload to ensure efficient delivery of all aspects of tasks

- Office Management
- Materials Management
- Men Management
- Computer Operations
- Client Management
- Maritime Security
- 70 words per minute typing
- Regular user of Microsoft Office, including Excel, Word and Powerpoint
- Highly organised and efficient
- Excellent English communication skills, both written and verbal
- Security and fire fighting
- Security Measures
- Handling of weapons
- Polite and professional manner
- High level of attention to detail
- City & Guilds MSO course qualified

#### **CAREER HISTORY**

Maritime Security Officer, Ambrey Risk , Maritime Security Team Leader from Oct 2015

(Dec 2012 - Present)

Working as maritime Security Team Leader on various vessels to ensure that ship's operations may continue without interference from criminals, militants, pirates or terrorists and to advise the Leader

#### **VED PRAKASH**

of the team in all matters pertaining to security.

# To provide:

- Ship security audit and report.
- Oversight and assistance with procuring and fitting hardening measures.
- A plan for the organization and conduct of security responses, and standard operating procedures for such responses – compiled with Master and based upon the Security Plan and Procedures document provided by IMSA.
- Assisting in briefing, training and drilling of ship's crew.
- Advice and encouragement to crew and DPO/CSO/SSO on maritime security.
- Enhanced surveillance by seeking and interpreting incoming live intelligence for the Master, and standing additional bridge lookout.
- Response with the managed and practiced assistance of the crew to any attempt to approach or board the vessel.
- Orchestration of withdrawal of crew to citadel.
- Communication between Master and outside security assistance during an incident.
- Incident reporting: Maintain an IMSA log.
- Daily sitrep to Team leader.
- Leadership.
- Provide 24/7 on call support.
- Responsible for the availability and continuous serviceability of any security equipment.

Associate Prehari Manager, DLF Pramerica Life Insurance Coy Ltd.

### (Feb 2013 – Mar 2013)

- Overseeing all administrative tasks of my area, including enrolment of Officer Praharis and Sales agents to sell the companies Insurance product to the defence personals only.
- Office administration, obtaining telephone connection, estate management, procurement/ logistics.
- Managing presentation and appointments regarding the Insurance plan "OP RAKSHAK" to the Key holder of the units and further guidance to troops to sell the insurance product.
- Up keeping & maintaining the discipline, security, reporting of all day to day activities done by me and my subordinates to the higher level.
- Working in close coordination with management and units.
- Organizing events and social gatherings during raising day of the units.
- Financial sponsorship to unit

Clerk/Quartermaster/Supervisor, Army Ordnance Corps (1995-2011)

## STOCKTAKING OFFICER (2009-2011):

- Ensure and certify that the assets on the list supplied by the asset management unit are accounted for.
- Ensure that missing assets are noted and action taken to locate them.
- Advise the Asset management Section of any assets that are obsolete, unused or missing and need to be written off.
- Details the circumstances relating to any assets declared missing (for example, steps taken to locate such assets).

#### VFD PRAKASH

- Ensure the correctness of details of entries listed.
- Advice the Asset management section of any asset those are not included in the list of assets.
- Sign and submit to the commandant statement that includes the proper custody and valuation of asset under their control.

### QUARTERMASTER CLERK AND WORKS OFFICER (2006-2009):

- Provision, preservation and issue of Ordnance stores to units and personals.
- Provision of Ration for the personals of units.
- Maintenance of vehicle records of unit.
- Maintain records of ordnance stores
- Timely submission of reports and returns
- Keep a current inventory of troop's equipment and sees that it is in good condition.
- Issue equipment and make sure it's returned in good condition.
- Work closely with the troop's committee equipment coordinator.
- Plan and work out for repairs to be carried out for maintenance of unit and project the same to Garrison Engineer and Chief engineer of the station for pricing, approval and implementation of work
- Follow up the works projected to Garrison Engineer for early implementation.

### **HEAD CLERK/LOCAL PURCHASE OFFICER (2003-2006)**

- Supervising all office activities.
- Procurement of stores from the local market to materialize the store which are not available in Ordnance store
- Ask for quotation and prepare Comparative statements
- Place supply order on dealers to supply stores
- Receipt of stores and inspect them for its correctness.
- Taking of stores by means of certified receipt voucher.
- Preparations of contingent bills and forward the same to Controller of Defense account for payment to dealers.
- Maintenance of local purchase documents and their audit.
- Timely verification of Dealers documents for genuine and good quality of stores supply.

#### **INVENTORY CONTROL CLERK (2000-2003)**

- Maintain records of all files and registers pertaining to depot stores.
- Submitting all reports and returns pertaining to stores to higher HQs.
- Routine correspondence as reply to letters received from various units pertains to store management.
- Vetting of demands received from various unit and process the demand by checking authorization through WET/PET and issue the demanded stores accordingly of issue voucher.
- Issue of stores to units on issue voucher.
- Maintenance and updating of Receipt vouchers received from units.

#### **VED PRAKASH**

Any other task allocated by Control Officer.

### PERSONAL ASSISTANCE (1996-2000)

- Assisting Commandant in his daily works.
- Perusal of letters received from outside.
- Sorting out important letter, give remarks, put up to commandant for his perusal and forward the same to concerned department for their further necessary action and follow up.
- Passing out all order given by Commandant to lower levels.
- Monitory of all activities in depot and report to Commandant at the end of day.
- Maintenance of personal document of commandant.

### **TRAINEE (1995-1996)**

 Gained training in Materials Management from College of Materials Management, Jabalpur and awarded Diploma in Materials Management

### **Additional duties**

- Continuously engaging in consultations & threat evaluation to ensure physical security of Men
   & Material.
- Involving in planning & execution of various security related contingencies to meet any eventuality/ crisis.
- With extensive and intensive experience in Resource Management, HR, Administration, Security management and Operations.
- Reputed for developing operational policies, procedures, establishing operational and service standards and implementing them.
- Well known for planning and implementing effective control measures.
- Valued contributor to key strategic initiatives right from conceptualization to facilitating implementation in real time environments.
- Enterprising Team Leader with the ability of handling large taskforces in a disciplined and organized manner as well as mentoring and motivating teams in optimizing performance levels.

#### **EDUCATION**

Graduate from Ministry of Defence
Diploma In materials Management-1995
CBSE Intermediate – 1994
Security Officer course, Secunderabad- 2011
STCW 95 – 2012
DSSD – 2013
City & Guilds MSO course – 2013

### **VED PRAKASH**

Painting and gaining maximum knowledge on computers

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Date of Birth - 12 May 1976
Father's Name - Ex Sub Prem Chand

Languages Proficiency - English, Hindi, Panjabi, Dogri and Gujarati

Marital Status - Married

**Passport Details:** 

 Passport No.
 :
 K169125

 Date of Issue
 :
 15-01-2013

 Expire date
 :
 14-01-2023